sam hindmarsh

♥ @hndmrsh in hndmr.sh/lnkd

about

I have a passion for crafting beautiful experiences. My focus has always been on delivering software which prioritises the user experience by combining delightful design and thoughtful interactions. However, I understand that such an experience is unattainable without a solid foundation to build off; hence, I am equally passionate about building apps using good engineering practices and strong architectural patterns. My eye for detail and evolving engineering principles has given me a platform for building great apps.

experience

Senior Android developer Apr 2019–Oct 2019 (contract)

Alphero

A six month contract which gave me the opportunity to work with many different clients on many different projects. Working on so many projects in a short space of time has helped me improve my ability to quickly pick up and learn new codebases (which vary in architecture, age, and technologies), as well as deliver features to deadlines. It has also helped me learn how to work with different clients, and adapt to their varying processes.

- Worked primarily individually to do bug fixes and minor improvements to a range of apps, including Metservice, RNZ, Nova Energy, and more.
- Responsible for adding new functionality to an app used internally at a government department.
- Worked alongside an iOS developer to understand and implement a new advertising framework for TVNZ OnDemand (for both mobile devices and Android TV).
- Worked on a number of research projects, including building a prototype machine learning-based recommendation engine, and a prototype Actions on Google (i.e. Google Assistant) app.



Sam@hndmr.sh □ +64 27 413 3772 ♦ hndmr.sh

@hndmrsh in hndmr.sh/lnkd

Open Company of the Company of

Senior Android developer Feb 2017-Apr 2019

Trade Me

My primary responsibility was development on the main Trade Me app, which has grown from humble roots to a complex product.

- Feature development using an in-house MVVM-based architecture.
- Unit testing, code reviews, and general practice improvement.
- Responsible for helping size and prioritise work.
- Aided in interviewing candidates for roles in the team.
- Provided input into product ideation and helping to solve the problems we faced.
- Responsible for evangelising mobile across a traditionally-desktop focused company.
- Mentoring of both a newly-hired junior Android developer, and another internal person interested in becoming a developer.
- Involved in reviewing proposed API changes to ensure backwards compatibility and provide suggestions from a mobile-consumer point of view.

Android developer Apr 2016-Dec 2016

Leaping Tiger

Leaping Tiger was a small local startup with a product designed to connect gamers to their local communities. During my time with the company, the main product features we built included a social feed for keeping up with friends' gaming activity; the ability to see events hosted in your local community; and reading announcements and news from the team.

- Sole Android developer responsible for developing the app independently.
- Responsible for building the app up from a WebView-based app to a modern native app using an MVP architecture and Material Design.
- Contributed much of the UI design and some development of the Rails API.
- Aided in product ideation and development.
- Helped the team adopt an Agile approach and upskill in these practices.



✓ sam@hndmr.sh □ +64 27 413 3772 ♥ hndmr.sh

Ø @hndmrsh in hndmr.sh/lnkd

Android developer Dec 2012-Apr 2016

Trade Me

I initially started at Trade Me as an intern through the Summer of Tech programme, continuing on part-time as I went back to uni to do my Masters' degree, and eventually joining the team on a full-time basis upon completion. Throughout my time at Trade Me, my primary responsibility was development of the main Trade Me app.

- Sole responsibility for building a homescreen widget.
- Contributed to a major structural change around search results.
- Implemented a redesign of the home screen and app navigation.
- Initiated and championed new internal libraries for code reuse and consistency between products.
- Sole designer and developer for an (unreleased) Android Wear app.
- Continuous feature development using an MVP architecture.

Due to my interest in improving team process (and a belief that our team could be operating more efficiently), I volunteered to take on the squad master role. This involved helping our team continually improve its Agile development processes in order to increase the quality, quantity and reliability of deliverables.

- Learnt and applied new techniques for running retrospectives.
- Adopted a new method of backlog sizing (T-shirt sizes) to cut down on time spent in meetings.
- Proposed a switch to Kanban from Scrum to reduce process overhead.

sam hindmarsh

🔰 @hndmrsh 🛮 **in** hndmr.sh/lnkd

android skills

- · Development using both Kotlin (preferred) and Java
- Unit testing with libraries such as Mockito
- Experience with libraries including RxJava, Dagger, Koin, Retrofit/OkHttp, Android Jetpack (Navigation/Lifecycle/Room)
- Experience with building and integrating Firebase backend solutions
- Experience with MVP and MVVM design patterns
- Some experience with setting up CI/CD pipelines

other relevant skills

- Hobby-grade experience with game development, using a Unity + Blender workflow to prototype games, resulting in participation in several game jams (Ludum Dare & Global Game Jam)
- Developed a simple working knowledge of C# through Unity scripting
- Basic ability with scripting in languages such as bash
- Experience with backend and API development in node.js
- Experience building static web pages using Jekyll

education

Master of Engineering 2013-2014

Victoria University of Wellington

Graduated with Merit. Received Masters by Thesis scholarship. My thesis investigated how improved experiences could be achieved with alternative keyboards and text input methods.

Bachelor of Engineering 2009-2012

Victoria University of Wellington

Graduated with First Class Honours. Included on Dean's List for academic excellence in 2012.